Who do you think
they are to each other?
Hm...
I don't know.
Yeah, this is a hard one.
I think
the white guy and the Asian girl
are a couple,
and the Asian guy
is her brother.
Or the Asian girl
and the Asian guy are a couple,
and the white guy
is their American friend.
They're not even talking
to the white guy.
Maybe they are tourists,
and the white guy is
their tour guide.
Drinking at 4:00 a.m.?
Yeah, you're right,
that makes no sense.
Hm. Maybe they're
all just colleagues?
I have no idea.
Na Young.
Why are you crying?
Are you crying because you got
second-best marks in the exams?
Are you mad at me
because I got first place?
Yes.
Hey! I'm always
second place to you,
but I never cry.
If I beat you
for the first time ever and you cry,
how do you think
that makes me feel?
You psycho.
Don't come in!
Talk from over there.
We decided.
What did you decide?
My name will be Michelle,
and Si Young's will be Mary.
I thought Si Young said
that she wants to be Michelle.
Why would you take
your sister's name?
I don't have
an English name I like.
Na Young,
you still shouldn't take Si Young's name.
But I hate all the names.
Let's think more about it.
How's Leonore?
For short, Nora.
Nora.
Nora Moon.
Na Young.
Hm?
Who do you
like at school nowadays?
What do you want to draw?
Ah, I'm thinking two things.
I want you to draw a tree.
Tree?
That's what I'm good at.
A tree doesn't have feelers.
Hae Sung.
Why?
He's manly.
He's manly?
Hm. Yeah. I will
probably marry him.
Really?
Does he want to marry you, too?
He likes me,
so he will if I tell him to.
Do you want to go
on a date with him?
They look so good together.
Hae Sung talks
about Na Young a lot.
Na Young told me
that she likes him.
We're immigrating soon.
So I wanted to make
good memories for her.
You're immigrating?
Yes.
But why are you immigrating?
Na Young's dad
is a film director,
and you're an artist.
Why would you leave
all that behind?
If you leave something behind,
you gain something, too.
It all looks
the same to me.
- Black barks and white...
- What is it?
This is called "blue".
This is called "yellow".
You're really leaving?
Yeah.
You're never coming back?
No.
Why are you leaving?
Because I want to.
Why do you want to leave?
Because Koreans don't win
the Nobel Prize for Literature.
Bye!
Na Young, take care!
Bye.
Hey.
What?
Bye.
- Hello.
My name is Nora,
what's your name?
My name is Michelle.
How are you, Michelle?
I'm fine, and you?
- I'm fine, and you?
I'm...
Toronto Pearson
International Airport...
Toronto Pearson International
Airport...
Na Young, Si Young!
Let's go.
Hurry up!
This is from Korea.
This is our passport, and...
Whoa!
I mean, there is
so much in it that... that I responded to.
But the one phrase that sticks
with me most...
- Mm-hmm.
- "The long journey of rotting."
I liked it, too.
We liked how you
used the long pauses.
Woah, Dong Yun...
He's a lawyer now.
He was a really good kid.
He helped me cover up
when I peed my pants in class.
You'd pee
your pants all the time.
A bedwetter lives
in New York City.
Yeah.
This bedwetter is killing it.
Who else should we look up?
- What's his name?
- Hmm?
The boy
I had a massive crush on?
I went on a date with him.
Hmm...
- Uh... Jung Hae Sung.
- Hae Sung.
Whoa! Mom, this is crazy.
He posted on Dad's movie's
Facebook page asking for me.
What are you talking about?
He posted a few months ago.
"I am looking for Na Young...
I am her childhood friend.
I want to get in touch
with her."
Wow. Really?
Let me call you back
in a minute.
Okay.
Um...
Oh, shit.
Hae Sung! This is Na Young.
Do you remember me?
Listen...
This is a good thing...
It's a good thing!
Think of it as
a blessing that you broke up,
and consider this
a new beginning.
There are a lot of women in the world.
Don't worry!
Shit, I must be an idiot...
Why do I miss that bitch?
Of course you miss her,
you moron!
If you don't miss her
after being with her
for two years,
are you even human?
Hey, no problem. Cry hard.
Hey.
This is a good thing...
a good thing!
She didn't deserve you.
This is a good thing.
Hey!
Do you have a secret
girlfriend or something?
What are you
talking about?
Who's messaging you
at 3:00 a.m.?
I have no idea.
Huh?
Hae Sung, wake up!
Thank you for this meal.
Did you drink a lot last night?
Hmm.
Kind of.
Why are you in such a good mood?
Woah.
It's you.
I recognize you.
You, too.
I didn't even know
that you remembered me.
I just looked for you
as a joke...
then I saw that
you'd been looking for me.
It wasn't a joke for me.
I tried really hard to find you.
It looks like you changed
your name?
Yeah. It's Nora now.
That's why I couldn't find you.
Can I just call you Na Young?
Of course.
But nowadays my mom
doesn't even call me Na Young.
Oh.
It looked like
you're in New York.
Yeah, I'm...
a writer here.
A playwright.
Hmm.
Kinda like your father.
Yeah.
Hey, that's cool.
Hmm, oh...
Hello?
Can you hear me? I'm here.
Hmm.
Are you home?
Yeah. I have to go
to class later.
My mom says
your school is a good one.
It's not bad.
I guess you got good grades.
I was ordinary.
We used to compete
a lot in school.
You cried because
you lost to me.
I lost once.
Do you still cry a lot?
No.
Really?
You used to cry a lot
back in those days.
Almost every day.
You would stay with me
whenever I was crying.
Hmm.
Why don't you cry now?
You can't cry in New York City?
Hmm...
When I first immigrated,
I used to cry a lot,
but then I realized
that nobody cared.
I see.
What do you study at school?
Uh... Engineering.
I know nothing about that.
I like this.
What?
Just...
talking to you.
Yeah?
I'm a really fun person
to talk to.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Hmm.
I gotta go to class.
Me, too. I have to eat dinner.
You haven't eaten dinner yet?
Not yet.
Hmm... What time is it there?
Hmm. Midnight.
And you still haven't eaten?
No.
Go and eat right now.
I will.
What?
It doesn't make sense but...
I'm not sure if I can say
something like this.
What do you want to say?
I missed you.
Me too.
- Hmm.
- It doesn't make any sense.
Umm, I really have to go now.
Class is starting soon.
Okay. Bye.
Let's talk again.
We should talk again.
- I'll send you an email.
- Hmm.
- Bye.
Hey.
Is it 7:00 in the morning there?
I thought you said you never
wake up before 10:00.
You said this is the only time
that works for you.
Don't you have class today?
Yeah.
So I left home early.
How was rehearsal today?
Your Korean is rusty.
Hey!
I only speak Korean with you
and my mom.
You said you're leaving Korea
to win the Nobel Prize.
You still want that?
Hmm...
Nowadays,
I'm really interested
in the Pulitzer.
You're the same as
the 12-year-old kid I remember.
Greedy?
Wants to do everything,
wants to have everything.
Has a terrible temper.
Exactly.
No, no, I'm kidding.
So you're writing there
the whole month?
Yeah.
It's an artist residency.
Can you see?
That's cool.
Where's Montauk?
Hmm... From New York
about four hours east?
Eternal Sunshine
of the Spotless Mind.
Have you seen it?
What did I do?
I love you so much.
I'll do anything to make
you happy.
Tell me what you want me
to do and I'll do it.
Would you
ever come to New York?
Why would I go to New York?
Why are you going to China?
To learn Mandarin.
You should come to New York
to learn English.
I always wanted
to learn Mandarin.
It's also helpful for my work.
That's good.
That's all I know.
Hello?
Hae Sung?
Na Young?
Can you hear me?
Hae Sung?
We're here.
You can see all of Seoul
from up here.
It's beautiful.
Wish I were there.
We should come here together.
I miss you.
Hello?
Would you
ever come to Seoul?
Why would I go to Seoul?
Have you done your homework?
I haven't.
You have to do it
for graduation.
I got under academic probation
last semester.
- Mm-hmm.
- Class captain's message.
Let me see your homework.
Maybe next time.
- I'm going.
- Oh. Huh?
Bye.
What's your plan for the weekend?
Playing games.
Hi.
You're not asleep yet?
Not yet.
You okay?
Of course.
What did you want to talk about?
When is it possible for you
to come visit me in New York?
A year and a half or so,
because of my language
exchange program and...
You don't have
to explain yourself.
It'll be at least a year
before I can come visit you in Seoul.
I want us to stop talking
for a while.
Why?
I immigrated twice to be here
in New York.
I want to accomplish
something here.
I want to commit
to my life here,
but I'm sitting around looking
up flights to Seoul instead.
So you want
to stop talking to me?
Just for now.
It took me 12 years
to find my friend.
I'll be back before you know it.
We're just taking a brief break.
I think it's a good idea.
Why am I like this?
I'm sorry.
What are you sorry about?
Were we dating or something?
Okay.
Bye.
Talk to you later.
Okay.
Talk then.
Are you okay?
We walked around a lot.
My leg's a bit hurt,
but I'm okay.
- This leg hurt?
- It's okay.
- Rock, paper, scissor.
- No, thanks.
Hae Sung, you're late.
We're here because of you.
You all packed?
Almost.
So when are you flying out?
This Sunday.
So you'll be there all summer?
Hey, tonight we drink
'til we die.
Why is he like this?
Hell yeah!
If Hae Sung says we drink,
we drink.
Another soju, please!
Hi.
Hi! I'm Nora.
I'm Arthur. Nice to meet you.
When'd you get in?
This morning.
- You got the worst room.
- Right?
I know.
There is a word in Korean.
In-Yun.
It means "providence".
Or... "fate".
But it's specifically
about relationships
between people.
I think it comes from Buddhism
and reincarnation.
It's an In-Yun
if two strangers even walk by
each other in the street
and their clothes
accidentally brush.
Because
it means there must have been
something between them
in their past lives.
If two people get married,
they say it's because there
have been 8,000 layers
of In-Yun.
over 8,000 lifetimes.
You believe in that?
Believe what?
That...
you and I knew each other
in another life.
What, because we are
sitting here...
...at the same table
in the same city
- in the same time?
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah, wouldn't that make this
an In-Yun?
Mm...
- Mm-mm.
- Mm.
That's just
something Koreans say
to seduce someone.
- Hi.
Where you going?
New York City.
Why're you going there?
We live there.
What's your occupation?
Writers.
You're what?
We're writers.
How long
were you visiting Toronto?
Ten days.
What was the purpose
of your visit?
We were visiting her family.
Are you two related?
We're married.
Thanks!
Hey.
"If you bought
a ticket to see this show,
"took the subway or a cab
to be here,
"it cost you something
"and spend a couple hours
with these old women,
"that makes you
some kind of immigrant.
"And all this cost me
something, too.
"I crossed the Pacific Ocean
to be here.
"Some crossings
cost more than others.
"Some crossings you pay for
with your whole life."
...sit most of the day,
and in the end I...
And then I started
to write about...
After Dinner.
Um, yeah, I mean,
it's my kind of time.
Uh, but you're studying, right?
I'm hungry.
Me, too.
What do you want to eat?
I don't know.
Ah...
What can I do?
- You know what I want?
- What?
Chicken wings.
Holy shit.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Oh, genius.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yes.
Chicken wings!
Mm...
What're you thinking about?
Remember I told you
about Hae Sung?
Oh, yeah.
Is that this week?
Yeah.
Why is he coming here again?
I think vacation.
Why are you going
to New York?
Vacation.
Rest, enjoy, have fun.
You're not going there
to see that girl, right?
Who?
Why are you pretending
not to know who I'm talking about?
Your first love.
I thought she lives there.
You gonna see her now that
you broke up with your girlfriend?
You think I'm nuts?
She's married.
Really?
Hmm.
I think it's been
about seven years.
She married early.
Ah,
you poor bastard.
What?
It's going to rain
the whole time you're there.
Look. "Severe thunderstorm".
Hey, don't forget
your rain boots and raincoat.
It really does say
"severe thunderstorm."
Uh, trunk? Trunk?
Hae Sung!
Woah. It's you.
Ah, what can I do?
What should I say?
I don't know.
Was the last time we talked
twelve years ago?
Glad the weather is nice today.
You're right.
Should we go?
Yes.
Before I got married,
I went to Korea with my husband.
I know.
I emailed you,
but you didn't respond.
I wanted to see you.
I was disappointed.
I'm sorry.
I wanted
to meet your girlfriend, too.
How are you two doing?
We're not together
right now.
You broke up?
No.
It's not that.
We just need time to think.
We just started talking
about getting married.
Do you not want
to get married?
I don't know.
If you love her,
why don't you know?
It's a little complicated.
What's complicated?
The conditions are not met.
What do you mean?
I'm an only child.
If you're going to marry
an only son,
he should make more money
and be better.
I'm too ordinary.
You're ordinary?
My job is ordinary,
my income is ordinary.
It's all ordinary.
She should meet someone
more impressive than me.
Is it hard to get married
if you don't make a ton of money?
At first we didn't think so,
but then
we started thinking that way.
Want me to take a photo of you?
Okay.
You look good.
Would you and your husband
come out here often on dates?
Hmm.
We lived near here before
we moved to the East Village.
We did all our dating here.
We would fight here, too.
- You two fight?
- Oh yeah, we don't fuck around.
Why do you fight?
Just because.
It's like planting two trees
in one pot.
Our roots
need to find their place.
Does your husband
get along with your family?
Yeah. He plays Hwa-Too
with them all the time.
He plays Hwa-Too?
Of course.
He knows how?
He's good.
Is his Korean good, too?
No.
But he can say a few things.
Oh, yeah?
His favorite food
is Yook-Gae-Jang.
Yook-Gae-Jung?
He's not fucking around.
Do you and your girlfriend...
fight?
No.
She's not really
my girlfriend right now.
You should get married well.
You're worrying about me?
Getting married is hard for
idealistic people like you.
Hey, I'm not so old
that you should worry.
Hae Sung.
Hmm?
Why did you look for me?
- 12 years ago?
- Hmm.
Do you really want to know?
I just wanted to see you
one more time.
I don't know.
Because you just left
so suddenly...
I was a little pissed off.
Sorry.
What are you sorry about?
You're right. There's nothing
to be sorry about.
You disappeared from my life,
and I just bam...
found you again.
Why would you do that?
I don't know.
Just because...
You kept entering my mind
when I was in the military.
I see.
We were babies then.
Right.
And when we met 12 years ago,
we were babies then, too.
We're not babies anymore.
- Hi.
- Hi, my love.
How was it?
You were right.
I was?
Yeah.
He came here to see me.
It's so crazy to see him
be this grown-up man
with a normal job
and a normal life.
He's so Korean.
He still lives with his parents,
which is really Korean.
And he has all these
really Korean views
about everything.
And I feel so not Korean
when I'm with him.
But also,
in some way, more Korean?
It's so weird.
I mean, I have Korean friends,
but he's not, like,
Korean-American.
He's Korean-Korean.
Is he attractive?
I think so.
He's really masculine
in this way
that I think is so Korean.
Are you attracted to him?
I don't think so.
I don't know, I mean...
He was just this kid in my head
for such a long time,
and then he was just this
image on my laptop,
and now he's a physical person.
It's really intense,
but I don't think
that that's attraction.
I think I just missed him a lot.
I think I missed Seoul.
Did he miss you?
I think he missed
the 12-year-old crybaby
he knew a long time ago.
You were a crybaby?
Yeah.
Most of the time he'd have to
just stand there and watch me.
When is he leaving again?
Morning after tomorrow.
Mm-hmm.
Are you mad?
No.
It feels like you are.
I don't have
a right to be mad.
What do you mean?
Of course, you do.
No...
That guy flew
13 hours to be here.
I'm not gonna tell you
that you can't see him
or something.
He's your childhood sweetheart.
And it's not like you're gonna
run away with him.
Are you?
Definitely. I'm gonna
throw away my life here...
...and run away with him to Seoul.
Do you even know me?
I'm not gonna miss
my rehearsals for some dude.
I know.
I know you.
What?
I was just thinking about
what a good story this is.
- The story of Hae Sung and me?
- Yeah.
I just can't compete.
What do you mean?
Childhood sweethearts
who reconnect 20 years later
only to realize they were
meant for each other.
- We're not meant for each other.
- I know.
I know. In the story,
I would be the evil white American husband
standing in the way of destiny.
Shut up.
What do you not like about it?
Our story's just so boring.
We met at an artists' residency.
Slept together because we both
happened to be single.
We realized
we both live in New York,
so, we moved in together
to save money on rent.
We got married so you could
get a green card. So...
Oh, you make it sound
so romantic.
Right, that's what I'm saying.
I'm the guy
you leave in the story
when your ex-lover
comes to take you away.
He's not my ex-lover.
What if you met somebody else
at that residency?
What if there was
another writer from New York
who had also read
all the same books you had,
and watched all the same movies,
who could give you
useful notes on your plays,
and listen to you complain
about your rehearsals?
- That's not how life works.
- Oh.
Yeah.
But wouldn't you be
laying here with him?
This is my life,
and I'm living it with you.
Are you happy with it?
Is this what you
imagined for yourself
when you left Seoul?
When I was a 12-year-old?
Yeah. Is this what
you pictured for yourself?
Lying in bed in some
tiny apartment
in the East Village
with some Jewish guy
who writes books?
Is that what your parents
wanted for you?
You're asking me if you,
Arthur Zaturansky,
are the answer to
my family's immigrant dream?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
I know.
This is where we ended up.
This is where
I'm supposed to be.
Okay.
What?
It's just that you make
my life so much bigger.
And I'm wondering if I do
the same thing for you.
You do.
I'm just a girl from Korea,
you know?
And you're forgetting the part
where I love you.
I don't forget that.
I have trouble
believing it sometimes.
Do you know
you only speak in Korean
when you talk in your sleep?
- I do?
- Yeah.
You never sleep talk in English.
You only dream in Korean.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
You never told me that.
Well, sometimes
I think it's cute.
Sometimes, I don't know,
I guess I get scared.
Scared of what?
You dream in a language
that I can't understand.
It's like
there's this whole place
inside of you where I can't go.
I think that's why I've
been trying to learn Korean,
even though I know
it's annoying for you.
You want to understand me
when I'm dreaming?
Yeah.
I'm sure I'm just
saying gibberish.
- Hey.
Did you get home
safe last night?
Yeah.
Sorry I'm late.
Did you eat something?
No.
Eat this.
Is it for me?
I wanted to ask you yesterday...
What prize do you
want to win nowadays?
Hmm?
When you were little,
you wanted to win the Nobel Prize,
and 12 years ago you
wanted to win the Pulitzer.
What do you want to win now?
I haven't thought
of things like that recently.
Really?
Then think about it
for a moment.
There must be an award you want.
A Tony.
You really are exactly
the same as I remember you.
Still psycho?
Still psycho.
A little bit to your left.
One, two... three!
One more.
Why are you taking it
so close up?
Fine. Go back a little bit.
She's turned against us.
Hold on.
You look young.
Because of my green card,
we got married
a little earlier than planned.
He knows I'm coming over?
Of course.
He knows who I am?
Of course!
He wants to meet you.
Come in.
Um...
Hello.
Nice to meet you.
Uh, hi.
Nice to meet you, also.
His Korean is good.
No.
Uh...
Are you hungry?
- Hmm?
- Oh...
Hungry?
Ah, oh. Yes.
What would you like to eat?
Uh...
Pasta?
Pasta? Yeah.
You like pasta?
Yes.
- Okay.
- Let's get pasta.
- Pasta.
What did you two do today?
Uh...
The Statue of Liberty.
You took the ferry.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
It's, um, nice.
I've never been.
- What?
- Really?
Yeah, I've never
actually been there.
Hey,
you should take your husband.
Have we seriously
never been there together?
No.
When I was 24 years,
I, uh... Um...
Oh.
Military service?
Yes.
Oh, military service.
Right.
You know how Korean men have
mandatory military service?
Yeah, your dad talks about it.
How was it?
You like it?
Did you like it?
No.
Uh, but military and work, same.
Same?
Same? How?
Uh,
you have, um...
You have a boss.
Hmm.
There's overtime pay,
stuff like that here, right?
In Korea, you work
overtime all the time,
but there's no overtime pay.
There's no
overtime pay in Korea.
- Really?
- Mm.
You have to do
all of your boss's work first,
then you do your own work,
and then you can go home.
Late at night?
That's so hard.
It's, uh, very hard.
Hmm. Uh, work. Work is hard.
Hard physically or mentally?
Physically, or mentally?
Uh, yes. Uh, both.
Physical, very hard.
- Uh, and, um...
- Hmm. Mentally.
Uh, mentally, I'm strong.
Mm!
You're strong mentally?
Yes, right.
It was good that you immigrated.
Mm. I agree.
Korea is too small
of a country for you.
It's not enough
to satisfy your ambition.
I'm glad to have seen you.
Yeah.
And thank you for introducing
me to your husband.
I can tell he really loves you.
Hmm.
I didn't know that liking your
husband would hurt this much.
Yeah?
Hmm.
When we stopped talking,
I really missed you.
Did you miss me?
Of course.
But you met your husband then.
You got a girlfriend then, too.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Seeing you again
and being here
makes me
have a lot of weird thoughts.
What kind of thoughts?
What if I'd come
to New York 12 years ago?
What if you had
never left Seoul?
If you hadn't just left
like that,
and we just grew up together,
would I still have
looked for you?
Would we have dated? Broken up?
Gotten married?
Would we have had kids together?
Thoughts like that.
But the truth
I learned here is,
you had to leave
because you're you.
And the reason I liked you
is because you're you.
And who you are
is someone who leaves.
The Na Young
you remember
doesn't exist here.
I know.
But...
that little girl did exist.
She's not sitting here
in front of you,
but it doesn't mean
she's not real.
20 years ago,
I left her behind with you.
I know.
And even though I was only 12,
I loved her.
You psycho.
I think there was something
in our past lives.
Otherwise, why would we
be here together right now?
But in this life,
we don't have the In-Yun to be
that kind of person
to each other.
Because now, finally,
we're in the same city
for the first time
in 20 years...
We're sitting here
with your husband.
In this life, you and Arthur
are that kind of In-Yun to each other.
You two have
the 8,000 layers of In-Yun.
To Arthur,
you're someone who stays.
He's talking about you.
Who do you think
we were to each other
in our past lives?
I don't know.
Maybe... an impossible affair?
Between the queen
and the king's henchman?
Or maybe we were forced
to live together
in a political marriage,
and we were awful to each other.
Cheat on each other a bunch.
Say hurtful things
to each other.
Or maybe we were just sitting
next to each other
on the same train.
Why?
Just because that's what
our tickets said.
Maybe,
we were just a bird
and the branch it sat on
one morning.
I'm sorry we speak alone.
Uh, we will stop.
It's okay.
You haven't seen each other
in a long time.
I never thought I'd be
a part of something like this.
Hmm?
Sitting here with you.
Do you know what In-Yun?
Yeah. Nora told me about it
when we first met.
You and me.
Yeah. Yeah, you and I
are In-Yun too.
Right?
I'm really glad you came here.
It was the right thing to do.
Mm. I'm gonna
walk him to his Uber.
Okay.
Uh, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
Uh, come visit me in Korea.
Definitely.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Will it be here soon?
Hmm.
Two minutes.
Hey!
Na Young.
Hmm?
What if this is a past life
as well,
and we are already
something else to each other
in our next life?
Who do you think we are then?
I don't know.
Me neither.
See you then.
I'm sorry!
Building statues
In the park
Mosaic faces
Fading in the rain
Recalling memories of love
We're untouched
And unscathed
Is this really
A mystery life?
We all learn from
Our own mistakes
We stare, fall down stairs
Maybe you're
Too much for me
We cry out
Break my heart, now
You called it out
To stay here
A long car drive
Music in my head
Come from a place
I don't know where
Swear that stars
Are aligning but
On a faraway stair
On a torched midnight
A field of death
On those marble steps
We'll meet again in life
That's how it's done
And I would soon burn
That's how it starts
And I will soon know
Fall, fall
Falling down
In spite of it all
Fall, fall
Will we meet
Again and again?
Ooh